<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Changelog</title>
    <author email="">Mario Linke</author>
  </properties>
  <body>

   <release version="1.0.0" date="2009-05-30" description="The first stable version">
    	<action dev="lm" type="fix">
    	Bug in compare  
 		(Bug: 1722101, thanks Avihai).
      	</action>
    	<action dev="lm" type="fix">
    	Deserialization of JSON object breaks on array of bytes.  
 		(Bug: 1728214, thanks P. Wolny).
      	</action>
    	<action dev="lm" type="fix">
    	Invalid JSON serialization of empty string  
 		(Bug: 1744253 and 1958512, thanks P. Wolny).
      	</action>
    	<action dev="lm" type="fix">
    	ReflectionMethodHelper should support "is" getters  
 		(Bug: 1828028, thanks D. Carrillo).
      	</action>
    	<action dev="lm" type="fix">
    	JSON serialize don't work by Map (String,Object).  
 		(Bug: 1755893, thanks boci).
      	</action>
    	<action dev="lm" type="fix">
    	Incorrectly escapized backslash.  
 		(Bug: 1769131, thanks T. Zalusky).
      	</action>
    	<action dev="lm" type="fix">
    	Add additional Java date format (i.e. EST timezone).  
 		(Bug: 2164723, thanks T. Hein).
      	</action>
    	<action dev="lm" type="fix">
    	Support for Beans with properties with type java.net.URL.  
 		(Bug: 2164752, thanks T. Hein).
      	</action>
    	<action dev="lm" type="fix">
    	CsvParser throws exception when parsing certain data.  
 		(Bug: 1793604, thanks Ryan (rptsang)).
      	</action>
    	<action dev="lm" type="fix">
    	Using the field "class" to represent the java class name breaks IE since class is a special word.   
 		(Bug: 1784930, thanks amccarri).
      	</action>
    	<action dev="lm" type="fix">
    	 Multiple references to same bean from another bean.   
 		(Bug: 2759772, thanks gokturk3).
      	</action>
    	<action dev="lm" type="fix">
    	Support for Beans with properties with type Object.  
 		(Bug: 2477567).
      	</action>
    	<action dev="lm" type="fix">
    	NPE in ConversionIterator. 
    	This exception appaer, when the object is not null, but the toString method get null.   
 		(Bug: 2786172).
      	</action> 
      	
    	<action dev="lm" type="add">
    	Convert Objects per fields, not methods.
    	In some case it is better, the converter used the attributes per fields and not per method.
		This is better, if not exist for every body attribute a setter method. 
 		(Feature: 2786181).
      	</action> 
      	
	</release>

   <release version="0.5.0" date="2007-05-01" description="The second release with development status: Beta">
    	<action dev="lm" type="fix">
    	Can't create a new instance of StackTraceElement in Java 5  
 		(Bug: 1678348).
      	</action>
      	<action dev="lm" type="fix">
    	Classloaders issue: In muliple classloaders environment (like application container) it would
		be nice if Sojo could be loaded by parent classloader of classloader of the
		application. Solution: Replacing
		Class.forName(className) with Class.forName(className, true, Thread.currentThread().getContextClassloader()).  
 		(Bug: 1686733, thanks  B. Hunt).
      	</action>                    
    	<action dev="lm" type="fix">
    	Deserialization of JSON object breaks on valid unicode char.  
 		(Bug: 1686652, thanks  B. Hunt).
      	</action>
    	<action dev="lm" type="fix">
    	Deserialization of JSON object breaks on Timestamp.  
 		(Bug: 1688969, thanks  B. Hunt).
      	</action>
    	<action dev="lm" type="fix">
    	Methods: equals and compare are breaking.  
 		(Bug: 1692340).
      	</action>
    	<action dev="lm" type="fix">
    	JsonSerializer not Thread Safe.
		JsonSerializer.deserialize cannot be used in a Thread safe way, since the method delegates calls to satic parser JsonParserGenerate.
		A better way would be to generate the JsonParserGenerate with STATIC=false and use one Parser per JsonSerializer.    	  
 		(Bug: 1694100, thanks T. Huhtanen).
      	</action>
    	<action dev="lm" type="fix">
    	Repeated call of JSONSerializer with different value.
 		(Bug: 1705249, thanks T. Nagy).
      	</action>

      	                    
		<action dev="lm" type="add">  
		Sort List, Set, Map and Array there contains JavaBeans.
		(Feature Request: 1673100)
		</action>
		<action dev="lm" type="add">  
		Support for filtering by equals, hashCode and compare.
		(Feature Request: 1692337)
		</action>
		<action dev="lm" type="add">  
		Support for regexp by filtering.
		(Feature Request: 1706577)
		</action>
	</release>



   <release version="0.4.0" date="2007-03-04" description="This is the first release with development status: Beta">
    	<action dev="lm" type="fix">  
      	Inconsistences return types between Xml and Json Serializer: the return type from XmlRpcSerializer.deserialize is a list that contain a desterilized Object as first element 
      	but this is not the same in JsonSerializer.deserialize , as this method return the desterilized Object directly not in a List
 		(Bug: 1633051).
      	</action>                    
    	<action dev="lm" type="fix">  
     	XmlRpcSerializer is not thread safe in version 0.3. In version 0.2 of sojo the XmlRpcSerializer was a thread safe but in 0.3 this isn't true.
		The XmlRpcSerializer was changed, because so that is uniform to the other Serializer (JsonSerializer for example)
 		(Bug: 1632206).
      	</action>                    
    	<action dev="lm" type="fix">  
		By the org.xml.sax.helpers.DefaultHandler class in the
		characters-method can be data lose. The reason is to call this
		callback-method more than one times for more performance from the
		SAXParser. This is the case by the
		xerces implementation (org.apache.xerces.jaxp.SAXParserFactoryImpl). This
		can be a promlem by big XML-files.
 		(Bug: 1664621).
      	</action>                    

		<action dev="lm" type="add">  
		CSV data interchange
		(Feature Request: 1639781)
		</action>
		<action dev="lm" type="add">  
		Calculate over all values the hashCode. This is the complement to the ObjectUtil.equals - Method.
		(Feature Request: 1671151)
		</action>
		<action dev="lm" type="add">  
		CompareTo method for all objects (JavaBeans too)
		(Feature Request: 1671946)
		</action>						
		<action dev="lm" type="add">  
		Extend Serializer method deserialize:
		The Serializer get a second deserialize method with an additional parameter:
		public abstract Object deserialize(Object pvSourceObject, Class pvRootClass);
		So can deserialize Objects, where in the serialize isen't the class information.		
		(Feature Request: 1656910)
		</action>
		<action dev="lm" type="add">  
		Create ThrowableConverterInterceptor:
		Can add a ThrowableConverterInterceptor to the Converter.
		This interceptor transform a Exception to a ThrowableWrapper. The benefit
		of this Conversion is, that can wrap a Throwable instance and can do an
		StackTrace or show the ExceptionMessage without a knowledge of the original
		ExceptionClass. For example, the server thrown a 'HibernateException' and
		the client don't know the hibernate library. In the StackTrace you can see
		the StackTrace of the server.
		(Feature Request: 1662346)
		</action>
		<action dev="lm" type="add">  
		Add parameter to type by ConverterInterceptor (beforeConvert / afterConvert).
		This is more flexible to define the to class type.
		(Feature Request: 1662347)
		</action>
		<action dev="lm" type="add">  
		Set desired date format:CURRENT serialized with JSON: {"dob":"Tue Feb 20 10:25:19 EST 2007","id":10}
		DESIRED serialized form: {"dob":"02/20/2007","id":10}
		(Feature Request: 1664604, thanks J. Saremi)
		</action>
	</release>


   <release version="0.3.0" date="2007-01-08" description="The third release">
    <action dev="lm" type="fix">  
		Can't call twice time the method ObjectUtil.makeSimple. By the second call is the result the same,
		how call of method ObjectUtil.makeComplex
 		(Bug: 1622475).
      </action>                    
      <action dev="lm" type="fix">  
		The result-Maps of ReflectionMethodHelper are modifiable (e.g. getAllGetterMethod).
		This is critical, because this Map's are static. If one instance this map change, work all instances with this changed map.
 		(Bug: 1621357)
      </action>                 
      <action dev="lm" type="fix">  
		JsonSerializer serialize Map with no String key not correct. This mean, the key was ignored
 		(Bug: 1615199).
      </action>                 
      <action dev="lm" type="fix">  
		JsonSerializer don't wrapped in double quotes and using backslash escapes
 		(Bug: 1616053, thanks T. Nagy).
      </action>                 

      	<action dev="lm" type="add">  
		Filter for properties. Not all properties of a class want to include by converting objects. 
		Especial by interchange data are not all data (properties) relevant. 
		With a filter can select the (transient) properties, that are filtered by serialize objects
		(Feature Request: 1612707, thanks G. Greg).
		</action>	
		<action dev="lm" type="add">  
		Refactor package and class-names (remove common loggings library and replace with net.sf.sojo.core.NonCriticalExceptionHandler)
		(Feature Request: 1615202).
		</action>	
		<action dev="lm" type="add">  
		Remove all dependencies to external libraries
		(Feature Request: 1625003)
		</action>			
	</release>
	
   <release version="0.2.0" date="2006-11-06" description="The second release">
      <action dev="lm" type="fix">  
		Conversions don't detect cycels by Collections and Maps.
		This problem is occurrence, if Collections/Maps are nested in a other Collections/Maps.
 		(Bug: 1589317)
      </action>                 
      <action dev="lm" type="fix">  
		Only the call in the constructor CommonObjectUtil (true/false) is effected. 
 		(Bug: 1580303)
      </action>                 
      <action dev="lm" type="add">  
		Support for interchange format JSON.
		(Feature Request: 1580533)
      </action>                 
      <action dev="lm" type="add">  
		Support for interchange format XML-RPC.
		(Feature Request: 1583118)
      </action>                       
    </release>

   <release version="0.1.0" date="2006-10-15" description="The first version 0.1.0">
      <action dev="lm" type="add">  
	      serialize/deserialize complex object graph  (Feature Requests: 1576716). 
      </action>                 
      <action dev="lm" type="add">  
	      easy navigate on the complex object graph  (Feature Requests: 1576711). 
      </action>                 
      <action dev="lm" type="add">  
	      compare complex object graph  (Feature Requests: 1576709). 
      </action>                 
      <action dev="lm" type="add">  
	      copy or clone complex object graph  (Feature Requests: 1576708). 
      </action>                 
    </release>


<!--
      <action dev="lm" type="fix">           
      FIX
      </action>                    		

      <action dev="lm" type="update">
			UPDATE
      </action>                      

-->


  </body>
</document>
